Text-Only Version [Go To Full Site](https://www.npr.org/179878450)

[NPR](https://text.npr.org/) >

NPR Online Privacy Policy
=========================

Updated Wednesday, April 24, 2024 • 10:10 AM EDT

**Last Updated: June 28, 2023**

* * *

Please click on the [**NPR Privacy Snapshot**](#privacysnapshot) for an overview of our privacy practices, and continue reading our Privacy Policy below.

**Privacy Policy Scope**

Welcome to the NPR Privacy Policy. This Privacy Policy describes the personal information National Public Radio, Inc. and its affiliated organizations (collectively, "NPR," "we" or "us") collect or allow others to collect. This personal information may be collected from you and your computer or device used to access or other sites, the NPR App or other applications, email newsletters, NPR's podcast subscription services, features such as sponsorship credits and marketing messages, benefits provided by NPR on behalf of the NPR Network (a collaboration between NPR and participating Member stations), digital platforms, or other interactive services provided by NPR that link to or refer to this Privacy Policy (collectively the "NPR Services" or "our Services").

This Privacy Policy also explains how personal information may be used and shared and the choices you have to limit certain uses or sharing of that information.

This Privacy Policy applies only to the NPR Services and does not govern the separate websites, applications, newsletters, platforms and services of NPR Member stations or of any third parties that may link to or be linked to from the NPR Services.

If you have questions about this Privacy Policy, please [contact us](https://help.npr.org/contact/s/contact?request=NPR-Management).

* * *

**Table of Contents**

**Personal Information Collected Through Our Services**

_**Information You Provide**_

We and our service providers, which only use your data on our behalf, may collect any information that you choose to provide directly through our Services, when you engage with our Services to:

* Register for an NPR account, NPR podcast subscription service or benefit provided by NPR on behalf of the NPR Network (such as the NPR+ bundle of sponsorship-free podcasts that NPR may provide to certain donors to Member stations), application programming interface (API) content access, or any NPR email newsletter.  

* Register for an NPR tour, event, travel program, or any contest we sponsor.  

* Contact us with a message.  

* Participate in a survey.  

* Make a purchase from the NPR Shop.  

* Email, text or otherwise share a story from any of the NPR Services.  

* Post, upload, or otherwise submit to NPR a comment, story idea, essay, photo, or other content or user-generated material ("User Materials").  

* Apply for a job, internship or fellowship at NPR.  

* Express interest in donating to or donate to NPR or an NPR Member station.  

* Otherwise volunteer information to us or respond to a request for information through any of our Services.

We also may ask you to provide other information about yourself for various other purposes that we specify or make apparent at the time of collection.

When you engage with our Services, you may provide the following types of personal information:

* **Contact details and profile and account information**, such as your name, email address, postal address, telephone number, password, age, country of residence, travel-related information, or your favorite Member stations.

* **Payment information**, such as payment card details and billing information.

* **Communications and content preferences**, including when you contact us with questions, feedback or otherwise in a message to NPR, in your engagement with our Services, or in connection with your registration for an NPR account, NPR podcast subscription service or benefit provided by NPR on behalf of the NPR Network, application programming interface (API) content access, or any NPR email newsletter.

* **Marketing data**, such as your preferences for receiving our email newsletters and other communications, including marketing, fundraising, membership and other messages, and details about your engagement with them.

* **Job applicant data** when you use the [Careers](https://text.npr.org/series/750004/careers) section of the website, such as your employment history, and as otherwise described in the Job Applicants section below.

* **Donation information.** If you choose to donate to NPR or an NPR Member station through the NPR Services, or express interest in or request information about making donations, we may keep a record of these contacts that includes your name, contact information, information about benefits provided by NPR on behalf of the NPR Network or an NPR Member station (such as the NPR+ bundle), and other information about your donation or inquiry. If you choose to donate to an NPR Member station, your information may be collected by that Member station, subject to the Member station's privacy policy, and may be shared with NPR to provide you benefits on behalf of the Member station or to provide you NPR Services.

* **Event data**, such as the information you provide to an event venue or us when you register for an event or an NPR tour. This information may include information collected to purchase or obtain a ticket or screen visitors for security purposes.

* **Survey data**, such as the information you provide when you participate in a survey. This may include information such as date of birth, gender, information about your employment, education level, income level, geographic location, and demographic information such as race and ethnic origin and sexual orientation. Where required under applicable law, we will only process demographic information with your explicit consent.

* **Contest data** that you provide to participate in a contest, such as information about those who appeared in your submission or helped you prepare it.

* **User Materials** that you post, upload, or otherwise submit to NPR.

* **Other data** not specifically listed here, which we will use as described in this Privacy Policy or as otherwise disclosed at the time of collection.

**_Information Automatically Collected Through Technology_**

We, our service providers, and our vendors automatically collect certain information about your computer or device and your interactions with our Services through access logs, cookies, pixel tags and other tracking technologies. Depending on which NPR Services you use and how you access them, the information collected automatically may include:

* The Internet Protocol address (IP address) of your computer or device used to access the NPR Services or play podcasts or other media content downloaded through our Services.  

* The domain name of your Internet Service Provider.  

* The website, application, platform or service you visited before and after visiting an NPR Service.  

* Search terms you enter using the NPR Services or on a referring website.

* Your approximate geographic location information (derived from your IP address) and/or more precise information about the specific location of your device if you have given NPR explicit consent to receive this information for an NPR application on your mobile device.  

* The make, model, carrier and unique device identifier for your mobile device, the unique advertising identifier (for example, Google Advertising ID) that allows mobile applications running on your mobile device to gather data for purposes of serving targeted advertising or personalized or "interest-based" sponsorship credits, and other information about your computer or mobile device and its browser, operating system, settings and software. If you have an iOS mobile device, we may collect the Apple IDFA (a unique advertising identifier) if you have given NPR consent to receive this information for an NPR mobile application on your device.  

* Automobile make (for certain connected car platforms).  

* The dates, times, duration, frequency and other details of your interactions with our Services.  

* Your navigation path through the NPR Services, including any "favorites" you select, and patterns in the paths you take.  

* A list of files you download, listen to, view, email, text or otherwise share and other content preferences.  

* The amount of time spent listening to or viewing media files or pages.  

* Listening data collected both when you download and listen to podcasts or other media files. Listening data includes descriptions of the title, episodes, segments and sponsorship credits included in a podcast or other media file, time and date stamps for download and playback events (for example, when a file is downloaded and when playback of a particular segment or sponsorship credit starts, stops, is skipped or is paused), the unique advertising identifier for your mobile device (for example, Google Advertising ID), session IDs and information about the device or platform used to download or play a particular file. The producers of any independently produced podcasts we distribute may also collect the same types of listening data subject to their own privacy policies, which may differ from ours.  

* Information about your interactions with our email messages, such as links you click on and whether you open or forward a message, the date and time of these interactions, and information about the computer or device you use to read emails.  

* Any errors you encountered during your use of our Services

We make use of third-party services, such as analytics, programmatic digital sponsorship platforms, cookie data collection (including cookie identifiers), and linking services (collectively, "Analytics & Sponsorship Services"). These Analytics & Sponsorship Services may include:

* Google Analytics 4, Google Universal Analytics, Google Analytics Demographics and Interest Reporting, Remarketing with Google Analytics, Google Ad Manager, and the services of our other vendors. These Analytics & Sponsorship Services may use cookies, pixel tags, hash values, and other tracking and storage technologies to collect, receive, or share information (this shared information does not include your unhashed name or email address you register with NPR) from our Services and elsewhere on the Internet and use that information to analyze and measure our audience and target and evaluate the effectiveness of sponsorship credits and marketing messages in our Services.

* First-party cookies (such as the Google Analytics cookies) and third-party cookies (such as the Remarketing with Google Analytics and DoubleClick cookies) that may be used together to inform, optimize, and serve sponsorship credits based on your past interactions with our Services and other websites or services.

* In connection with an affiliate-marketing relationship with platforms such as Apple or online retailers, third-party analytics services working with us and such platforms or online retailers may also use cookies to uniquely identify the browsers of (i) users who click on marketing messages we display to promote our podcasts available through Apple Podcasts or iTunes and then later purchase a podcast subscription through Apple, or (ii) users who click on links to an online retailer in NPR content mentioning books, music, or other related merchandise and then later purchase that merchandise on the online retailer's site.

* When you use our Services and enter your email address on our Services (either to log in, or to sign up for a newsletter, or take similar actions), we may share with vendors, such as LiveRamp, information that we collect from you, such as a hash value based on your email address, IP address, or information about your browser or operating system. These vendors, such as LiveRamp, act as "joint controllers" (as applicable depending on the law where you live) in processing this information. Vendors, like LiveRamp, use this information to create an online identification code that we may store in our first-party cookie for our use in online, in-app, and cross-channel sponsorship and marketing messages, and for the purpose of recognizing your devices. This code does not contain any of your directly identifiable personal information and will not be used by vendors, such as LiveRamp, to determine your name or email address, or to otherwise directly identify you. The identification code may be shared with sponsorship vendors to enable "interest-based" and targeted sponsorship and marketing messages.

* In addition, we may use analytics data, including but not limited to, geographic, demographic, and interest reporting information to recognize and understand user preferences, make improvements, and for other operational purposes.

An Analytics & Sponsorship Service's ability to use and share information is covered by that service's terms of use and privacy policy. To learn more about how Google uses data, visit [https://policies.google.com/technologies/partner-sites](https://policies.google.com/technologies/partner-sites). Detailed information on LiveRamp's data processing activities is available in LiveRamp's privacy policy: [https://liveramp.com/privacy/](https://liveramp.com/privacy/).

Further information about our use of cookies, pixel tags and other tracking technologies can be found in our [Cookie Policy](https://text.npr.org/609791368) and in the "[Privacy Rights and Choices](#yourchoices)" section below.

**_Information We Obtain From Other Sources_**

* **Platform and public media single sign-on and sharing tools.** Our Services allow users to sign in to their NPR accounts using their credentials from platforms such as Apple, Facebook, and Google or from public media organizations such as our Member stations or PBS (each an "SSO Provider"). If you sign in to our Services through an SSO Provider, we will receive your email address and certain profile information from such SSO Provider in accordance with its privacy policy and your SSO Provider account privacy settings. Any information that we collect from your SSO Provider account may depend on the privacy settings you have selected with that SSO Provider, so please consult the applicable SSO Provider's privacy and data policies to learn how to manage these settings. If you use tools on our Services that allow you to share stories or other content with your friends and followers on an SSO Provider's platform such as Facebook, Flipboard, or Google, that action and any information you share may be used by the SSO Provider according to its own privacy policy.

* **Member stations.** We may obtain personal information from our Member stations to provide services on their behalf in accordance with their privacy policies or to provide our Services to you as otherwise described in this Privacy Policy.

* **Other third parties.** We may obtain personal information from other third parties, such as sponsorship and marketing vendors, event venues, publicly-available sources and data providers.

**How We Use the Personal Information We Collect**

We and service providers and vendors collect and use personal information to provide you with a customized interactive experience and to make our Services more valuable to you. We also may use this information for fundraising purposes to support our Member stations and public media mission.

NPR and service providers and vendors also may use the information collected through our Services:

To perform contractual obligations under our [Terms of Use](https://text.npr.org/179876898), including:

* To manage, administer and deliver the NPR Services.

* To publish, broadcast, attribute and otherwise use and license any User Materials you submit according to our [Terms of Use](https://text.npr.org/179876898).

* To fulfill your NPR Shop orders and other requests.

* To offer you access to NPR tours, events, and travel programs.

* To manage contests you enter.

It is in our legitimate business interests to use personal information:

* To respond to your questions or messages.

* To provide you with personalized features and content, including content from NPR Member stations that are associated with your account or located near you and other content that may be of interest to you. For example, we may track your choices with respect to listening data, websites visited, Member station chosen, and search terms in order to derive your interests and preferences.

* To save and "remember" your registration information, settings and preferences so you do not have to re-enter this information each time you visit.

* To understand whether and when you read our email messages and click on links in those messages.

* To improve the NPR Services.

* To process applications for jobs, internships and fellowships at NPR.

* To process applications for volunteers for our NPR Ambassador program.

* To contact you for an online or phone survey and process your responses, or for other editorial purposes (or with your consent where required).

* To generate aggregate or other information that is not reasonably linkable to you or your devices used to access our Services, and use and share that information for NPR's purposes. For example, we may share or authorize the collection of such information by service providers or vendors that help us analyze and improve our Services, provide us and other digital media organizations with ratings and ranking data, or help us to create personalized content.

We, our service providers, and our third-party sponsorship or marketing vendors may collect and use personal information for the following marketing, sponsorship, analytics, and operational purposes, on the basis of our legitimate business interests or consent where required by law:

* To provide personalized, "interest-based" or "cross-contextual" digital sponsorship credits and marketing messages.

* To recognize you as the same user when you access our Services, content, marketing messages and sponsorship credits using different computers, devices and browsers, and to deliver our Services, content, marketing messages and sponsorship credits to you on different computers, devices and browsers.

* To send you NPR email newsletters and other communications, including marketing, fundraising, membership and other messages from NPR or our Member stations.

* To control the sequence and frequency of sponsorship credits and marketing messages you hear and see, control the platform on which you hear and see sponsorship credits and marketing messages, and tailor the content of those messages to your perceived interests.

* To conduct market or audience analysis and related reporting, including attribution, conversion, and other analysis to evaluate the performance of sponsorship credits and marketing messages.

* To help us measure and analyze user traffic and usage patterns and improve the quality and effectiveness of content, features, sponsorship credits, marketing messages and other communications.

Where we seek your consent, you may withdraw your consent at any time.

We use personal information for compliance and protection purposes in our legitimate business interests, including:

* To prevent potentially prohibited or illegal activities, comply with applicable laws, lawful requests and legal process, such as to respond to subpoenas or requests from government authorities.

* To enforce our [Terms of Use](https://text.npr.org/179876898) [](#_msocom_1)or other legal rights.

* To protect our, your or others' rights, privacy, safety or property (including by making and defending legal claims).

* To audit our internal processes for compliance with legal and contractual requirements and internal policies.

**How We Disclose Personal Information**

NPR is committed to maintaining your trust. We want you to understand when and with whom we and service providers and vendors may share personal information about you that is collected through our Services.

**_The public or other individuals_**

Any User Materials you submit through our [Contact Us](https://help.npr.org/contact/s/contact?request=NPR-Management) page, social media services or similar features can be seen, collected and used by us and anyone else who has access to the applicable service. Any User Materials you submit may also be freely used and shared by NPR and its Member stations and their respective licensees in accordance with our [Terms of Use](https://text.npr.org/179876898). You may also choose to share stories or other content with your friends and followers on social media services. In addition, we may share your information with other individuals at your direction. For example, if you use our Services to email or text a story to a friend, we would disclose your name to that friend together with the content you directed us to send.

**_Member stations_**

NPR may share your name, email address, other contact information, and information about your subscriptions, benefits (such as the NPR+ bundle), listening and usage activity, donations and interests with the Member stations that are associated with your account, that are local to you, or that you have donated to using the NPR Services. When we do so, we require those Member stations to commit to the same policies regarding further sharing with third parties that we follow under this Privacy Policy. Member stations may use this information for internal purposes and to send you email newsletters and marketing, fundraising, membership and other communications. If you do not want us to share your information with Member stations, you can [contact us](https://help.npr.org/contact/s/contact?request=NPR-Management) to opt out as set out in the [Privacy Rights and Choices](#yourchoices) section below.

**_Authorized service providers_**

We may share any information we collect with service providers who provide us with specialized services or otherwise help us operate our Services including, without limitation, service providers that provide customer support, email deployment, account sign-in services, subscription services, payment processing, order fulfillment, analytics, marketing, sponsorship, suppression list management, travel program, contest management and data processing services.

**_Sponsorship and marketing vendors_**

Subject to applicable law and your opt-out choices described below and in our [Cookie Policy](https://text.npr.org/609791368), and as we deem appropriate, we may share with sponsorship and marketing vendors, including those who provide digital sponsorship credits and marketing messages for us, or allow them to directly collect information about your devices and your use of our Services. We will not share your name or contact information in unhashed form with these vendors. These vendors may use such information pursuant to their own respective privacy policies, which we do not control.

* For example, we may share or authorize the collection of such information by vendors that help us analyze and improve our Services (including sponsorship credits and marketing messages in our Services), or to tailor sponsorship credits and marketing messages to your perceived interests. In order to provide sponsorship credits and marketing messages tailored to your perceived interests, vendors may use and further share information with other third parties such as supply-side platforms or services (working with us) and demand-side platforms or services (working with us and sponsors) in order to enable "interest-based" sponsorship.

* As described above, we may work with third-party analytics services to set tracking cookies or pixels on browsers of users who click on marketing messages for podcast subscriptions sold through Apple Podcasts or iTunes, or users who click on links to an online retailer in content mentioning books, music, or other related merchandise and then later purchase that merchandise on the online retailer's site. We do this to measure the performance of these marketing messages and to facilitate the calculation of commissions we may receive when a person subscribes to one of our podcasts available through Apple Podcasts or iTunes, or when a person purchases the mentioned merchandise on the online retailer's site.

* For example, as described above, when you enter your email address on our Services (either to log in, or to sign up for a newsletter, or take similar actions), we may share with vendors, such as LiveRamp, information that we collect from you, such as a hash value based on your email address, IP address, or information about your browser or operating system. Vendors, like LiveRamp, use this information – which does not contain your directly identifiable personal information and which these vendors will not use to determine your name or email address, or to otherwise directly identify you – to create an online identification code that we may store in our first-party cookie for our use in online, in-app, and cross-channel sponsorship and marketing messages, and for the purpose of recognizing your devices. The identification code may be shared with sponsorship vendors to enable "interest-based" and targeted sponsorship and marketing messages.

_**Payment processors**_

If you wish to make a payment or receive a refund through our Services, your information will be collected and controlled by the payment processor and not by us and will be subject to that payment service provider's privacy policy and practices.

**_Professional advisors_**

We may share with professional advisors, such as lawyers, auditors, bankers and insurers, where necessary, in the course of the professional services that they render to us.

**_Authorized third-party applications_**

We may share with authorized third-party applications information that you provide directly through our Services and information collected automatically through technology for the purpose of providing certain NPR Services to you on the applications. In such cases, the information that we share may include your name, favorite Member stations, and listening and usage activity. NPR prohibits the third-party developers of those applications from accessing, storing or sharing any such information. However, please be aware that your use of the third-party application is otherwise subject to the third-party application's privacy policy, which we do not control and which may differ significantly from ours. NPR is not responsible for the privacy practices of any third-party application, and we recommend that you familiarize yourself with the privacy policies of any third-party sites, applications, platforms, and services that you visit or access.

**_Business transfers_**

We may share any collected information in connection with a substantial corporate transaction, such as the sale of an NPR Service or division, a merger, a consolidation, an asset sale, or in the unlikely event of bankruptcy.

**_Legal requirements_**

We and service providers and vendors may disclose any collected information to respond to subpoenas, court orders, legal process, and other law enforcement measures, and to comply with legal or regulatory obligations.

**_Protect our Services and users_**

We and service providers and vendors may disclose any collected information to enforce our [Terms of Use](https://text.npr.org/about-npr/179876898/terms-of-use) and to protect and defend the legal rights, interests, and safety of NPR, NPR Member stations, their respective employees, agents, contractors, sponsors, listeners and users, members of the general public, or others.

**_Wireless carriers and automobile manufacturers_**

Wireless carriers and automobile manufacturers also may collect contact and other information and precise location data from our mobile services users through processes we do not control. You should check the privacy policies of your wireless carriers and automobile manufacturers for additional information.

**_Podcast producers_**

We may share with third-party producers listening, usage and other data that does not identify you that we collect through your interaction with the podcasts and other media files produced by those third-party producers.

**_Bitly_**

NPR uses a service called Bitly to create shortened uniform resource locators (URLs – the addresses of individual web pages) for our content so that it can be shared easily, particularly through social media. Bitly collects information as our shortened URLs are shared and clicked on, including IP addresses, general location information, the time and day each shortened URL is accessed, and the social media or other channels through which our content is shared. If you have established a separate account with Bitly, Bitly may associate the foregoing information with personal information it has stored in your Bitly account in accordance with Bitly's own [privacy policy](https://bitly.com/pages/privacy). To share our content without using Bitly, copy the full URL of the story you want to share from your browser and paste it into your email, text or social media message.

**_Aggregated and anonymous information_**

Subject to applicable law and your opt-out choices described below, and as we deem appropriate, we may share with third parties or allow them to collect directly aggregated or other information that is not reasonably linkable to you or your devices. These third parties may use such information pursuant to their own respective privacy policies, which we do not control. For example, we may share or authorize the collection of such information by service providers or vendors that help us analyze and improve our Services, provide us and other digital media organizations with ratings and ranking data, or help us to create personalized content. We may also share or authorize the collection of such information by sponsors or their agencies to help them measure the impact of their sponsorship campaigns.

**Privacy Rights and Choices**

You have the following choices to update, correct and limit the collection and use of information gathered through our Services.

* **_Manage cookie settings and opt out of interest-based sponsorship credits and marketing messages on_** **.** You can manage your cookie settings, including accepting or rejecting cookies, by clicking the "Cookie Settings & Opt Out" button above. Clicking on that button, and following the instructions, will also allow you to opt out of the sharing of your information with our sponsorship vendors for delivery of "interest-based" sponsorship credits and marketing messages on . If you opt out, those vendors may continue to serve you non-personalized, non-interest-based sponsorship credits and marketing messages on . Note that this opt out is a cookie-based process and will only affect the specific computer, device, and browser on which your opt-out choice is applied. If you subsequently delete your browser cookies or if your browser cookies expire, you will need to opt out again. For additional information regarding the cookies and similar technologies used in the NPR Services and how to opt out of interest-based sponsorship and marketing messages, read our [Cookie Policy](https://text.npr.org/609791368).

* **_Blocking advertising ID use in your mobile settings._** Your mobile device settings can provide functionality to limit use of the advertising ID associated with your mobile device for interest-based sponsorship purposes.  
      
    For iOS mobile devices, go to "Settings" from your device's home screen, scroll down to find and select "Privacy," and then select "Tracking" to adjust tracking permission. For Android mobile devices, go to "Google Settings" on your device, select "Ads"; and click the option labeled "Delete advertising ID." (Please note these settings allow you to opt out of interest-based messages for all applications, not just NPR's mobile applications. These device settings options may change in the future or otherwise may differ for certain devices; consult your device manufacturer's support literature for the most current information.) As noted above, if you opt out, you may still receive the same number of sponsorship credits and marketing messages as before but they may not be as relevant to your interests. Because these opt out mechanisms are specific to the device on which they are exercised, you will need to opt out on every device that you use. For additional information regarding the cookies and similar technologies used in the NPR Services and how to opt out of "interest-based" sponsorship and marketing messages, read our [Cookie Policy](https://text.npr.org/609791368).

* **_Update or delete registration information._** Sign in to your NPR account or [contact us](https://help.npr.org/contact/s/contact?request=NPR-Management) to delete, correct, or update any registration information you provided to us or to cancel your NPR account or other NPR registrations. You can click [here](https://help.npr.org/contact/s/article?name=How-do-I-cancel-a-subscription-to-a-sponsor-free-podcast-feed) to learn how to cancel your podcast subscription Services or NPR+ bundle.

* **_Opt out of sharing donation information_****.** You can opt out of sharing your donation information at the time you make a donation or you can [contact us](https://help.npr.org/contact/s/contact?request=NPR-Management) at any time if you are a donor to NPR and do not want us to share your name, contact information or other information with any Member station or the NPR Network, or if you want to limit NPR's use of your information collected on behalf of Member stations. However, if you choose to donate to an NPR Member station through our Services, your information may be collected by NPR and/or by that Member station. If your information is collected by that Member station, the collection of your information is subject to that Member station's privacy policy.

* **_Opt out of sharing information with Member stations_****.** You can [contact us](https://help.npr.org/contact/s/contact?request=NPR-Management) any time if you do not want us to share your name, email address, other contact information, and information about your subscriptions, benefits (such as the NPR+ bundle), listening and usage activity, donations (described above) and interests, with Member stations or the NPR Network. If you want to limit NPR's use of your information collected on behalf of Member stations, you can [contact us](https://help.npr.org/contact/s/contact?request=NPR-Management) any time as well.

* **_Opt out of sharing for newsletter "interest-based" sponsorship._** To opt out of the sharing of your information with our newsletter sponsorship vendor for delivery of "interest-based" sponsorship credits and marketing messages through our email newsletters, please [contact us](https://help.npr.org/contact/s/contact?request=NPR-Management) or email us at [privacy@npr.org](mailto:privacy@npr.org).

* **_Opt out of marketing communications_****.** You can stop the delivery of marketing, fundraising, membership and other emails or email newsletters from NPR by following the unsubscribe instructions in any such email you receive or by [contacting us](https://help.npr.org/contact/s/contact?request=NPR-Management). You may continue to receive Services-related and other non-marketing emails.

* **_Opt out of sharing precise location information_****.** If you consent to our collection of your precise device location through an NPR mobile application, you can withdraw your consent at any time and prevent the further collection of your precise location by accessing the privacy settings of your mobile device and/or the settings of the NPR mobile application.

We also offer you choices that affect how we handle the personal information that we control. Depending on the applicable law in your jurisdiction and the nature of your interactions with our Services, you may request the following in relation to personal information:

* **Information** about how we have collected and used personal information. We have made this information available to you without having to request it by including it in this Privacy Policy.

* **Access** to a copy of the personal information that we have collected about you. Where applicable, we will provide the information in a portable, machine-readable, readily usable format.

* **Correction** of personal information that, under applicable law, is inaccurate or out of date.

* **Deletion** of personal information that we no longer need to provide the Services or for other lawful purposes.

* **Opt out of the sharing of your personal information.** We share personal information with sponsorship and marketing vendors that display or serve targeted sponsorship and marketing messages to users around the web and other online services. You can limit online tracking by clicking on the "Cookie Settings & Opt Out" button above, as described in our [Cookie Policy](https://text.npr.org/609791368), or by clicking "Your Privacy Choices" in the footer of our website. To opt out of the sharing of hash values based on your email address with our sponsorship vendors, such as LiveRamp, for delivery of "interest-based" sponsorship credits and marketing messages, please also [contact us](https://help.npr.org/contact/s/contact?request=NPR-Management) or email us at [privacy@npr.org](mailto:privacy@npr.org).

* **Additional rights**, such as to **object** to and request that we **restrict** our use of personal information.

To make a request, please email us or write to us as provided in the [How to Contact Us](#howtocontact) section below. We may ask for specific information from you to help us confirm your identity. For your protection, we may only act on requests with respect to the registration data associated with the particular email address that you use to send us your request, and we may ask you to verify your identity before implementing your request. We will try to comply with your request as soon as reasonably practicable, or comply as required by law. We may need to retain certain information for recordkeeping purposes and/or to complete any transactions that you began prior to requesting an update or cancellation. Depending on where you reside, you may be entitled to empower an "authorized agent" to submit requests on your behalf. We will require authorized agents to confirm their identity and authority, in accordance with applicable laws. You are entitled to exercise the rights described above free from discrimination.

In some instances, your choices may be limited, such as where fulfilling your request would impair the rights of others, our ability to provide a service you have requested, our ability to comply with our legal obligations and enforce our legal rights, or may interfere with our rights to free speech and free press or to engage in other protected journalism activities. If you are not satisfied with how we address your request, you may submit a complaint by contacting us as provided in the [How to Contact Us](#howtocontact) section below. Depending on where you reside, such as if you reside in the European Economic Area or United Kingdom, you may have the right to complain to a data protection regulator where you live or work, or where you feel a violation has occurred.

**Security**

We employ administrative, technical, and physical safeguards in an effort to secure the information we collect. These safeguards vary based on the sensitivity of the information. Because no security system is impenetrable, however, we cannot guarantee the security of our databases or that information you supply will never be intercepted, accessed, or disclosed in a manner that is inconsistent with this Privacy Policy. Because most email and mobile transmissions are not encrypted, you should take special care in deciding what information you send to us via email, text message, or other mobile transmissions.

**Children**'**s Privacy**

NPR cares about protecting the privacy of children. Our Services are not intended for use by children under 18 years of age. If we learn that we have collected personal information through the Services from a child under 18 without the consent of the child's parent or guardian as required by law, we will delete it.

**Retention of Personal Information**

Where required under applicable laws, we retain personal information for as long as is necessary to perform the processing described in this Privacy Policy, in accordance with our retention policies, and with applicable laws and regulatory obligations or until you withdraw your consent (where applicable).

To determine the appropriate retention period for personal information, we consider the amount, nature, and sensitivity of the personal information, the potential risk of harm from unauthorized use or disclosure of personal information, the purposes for which we use personal information and whether we can achieve those purposes through other means, and the applicable legal and regulatory requirements.

**Links to and from Other Sites and Services**

Our Services contain links to other sites, applications, platforms and services operated by third parties whose privacy policies we don't control and may differ significantly from ours. For instance, clicking or tapping on a sponsorship credit or some third-party logos on the NPR Services will take you to an entirely different site or service that may collect, use and share information in ways that NPR would not. You also may access NPR content and the NPR Services from a third-party site or service that may collect, use and share information in ways that NPR would not. NPR is not responsible for the content or privacy practices of these third-party services and we recommend that you familiarize yourself with the privacy policies of any such sites or services you visit or access.

**Job Applicants**

When you visit the [Careers](https://text.npr.org/series/750004/careers) portion of the website, we collect the information that you provide to us in connection with your application for a job, internship, or fellowship at NPR. This includes but is not limited to business and personal contact information, professional credentials and skills, educational and work history and other information of the type that may be included in a resume. This may also include demographic information that you voluntarily provide. We use this information on the basis of our legitimate business interests to facilitate our recruitment activities and process employment applications, such as by evaluating a job candidate for an employment activity, to monitor recruitment statistics and to respond to surveys. We may also use this information to provide improved administration of the Services and as otherwise necessary (i) to comply with relevant laws such as government reporting or to respond to subpoenas or warrants served on us, (ii) to protect and defend our or others' rights or property, (iii) in connection with a legal investigation, and (iv) to investigate or assist in preventing any violation or potential violation of the law, this Privacy Policy or our [Terms of Use](https://text.npr.org/about-npr/179876898/terms-of-use).

**Changes to This Privacy Policy**

NPR reserves the right to change this Privacy Policy at any time. Any changes will be posted to this page, so please check back periodically. Your use of our Services constitutes consent to the Privacy Policy then in effect. Please read our [Terms of Use](https://text.npr.org/179876898) to understand additional terms and conditions that apply to your use of our Services.

**International Data Transfers**

Our Services are controlled and operated within the United States. Any information we collect may be transferred to, and processed, stored, and accessed by, us, our service providers, and vendors in the United States and in other jurisdictions where we, our service providers, or vendors operate. These jurisdictions may have data privacy laws that may not be as protective as those of your home jurisdiction, and courts and other authorities may, in certain circumstances, be entitled to access information about you subject to such data privacy laws.

When we engage in cross-border data transfers, we will ensure that relevant safeguards are in place to afford adequate protection for personal information and we will comply with applicable data protection laws, in particular by relying on an EU Commission or UK government adequacy decision or on contractual protections for the transfer of personal information. For more information about how we transfer personal information internationally, please contact us as set out in the [How to Contact Us](#howtocontact) section below.

**How to Contact Us**

**Responsible entity**. National Public Radio, Inc. is the entity responsible for the processing of personal information under this Privacy Policy (as a controller, where provided under applicable law).

**Contact us.** If you have any questions or comments about this Privacy Policy, our privacy practices, or if you would like to exercise your rights with respect to your personal information, please [contact us](https://help.npr.org/contact/s/contact?request=NPR-Management), email us at [privacy@npr.org](mailto:privacy@npr.org), or write to us at:

National Public Radio, Inc.  
Attn: Data Protection Officer  
1111 North Capitol Street, NE  
Washington, DC 20002, USA

**Privacy Snapshot**

Here is a high-level snapshot of our privacy practices, but please read the entire Privacy Policy for complete information.

* * *

Topics

© NPR
